rust a memory safe compiled programming language that delivers high-level
rust 一种内存安全的编译编程语言，提供高级别的
simplicity with low-level performance it's a popular choice for building
简单性和低级性能它是构建系统的流行选择，这些
systems where performance is absolutely critical like game engines databases or
系统的性能是绝对关键的，如游戏引擎数据库或
operating systems and is an excellent choice when targeting webassembly it
操作系统，并且是针对 web 组装它
started as a side project of great on in 2007 who named it after the
开始作为一个方面的绝佳选择2007 年的一个伟大的妓女项目，
rust fungus it was sponsored by mozilla in 2009 and has been ranked the most
它以 2009 年由 mozilla 赞助的锈菌命名，自 2016 年以来每年都被评为
loved programming language every year since 2016 with its fans being known as
最受欢迎的编程语言，其粉丝被称为
rust stations traditionally high level languages provide a garbage collector to
锈站传统上高级语言提供垃圾收集器 为了
nerf your control over memory management while lower level languages provide
削弱您对内存管理的控制，而较低级别的语言
functions like free and allocate to shoot yourself in the foot rust takes a
提供诸如 free 和 allocate 之类的功能以使自己陷入脚锈采取了
different approach it has no garbage collector but achieves memory safety
不同的方法，它没有垃圾收集器，但通过
with a concept known as ownership and borrowing by default every variable in
称为所有权和默认借用的概念来实现内存安全
rust is immutable this allows values to be used in the stack memory which has
rust 是不可变的，这允许在 stac 中使用值 k 内存，它具有
minimal performance overhead however mutable values or objects with an
最小的性能开销，但是
unknown size at compile time are stored in the heap memory every value in a rust
在编译时可变值或大小未知的对象存储在
program is assigned to a single variable known as its owner when that variable
goes out of scope the memory allocated to it is dropped automatically in some
堆内存中在某些情况下，分配给它的对象会自动删除，
cases though you may want to pass a reference to a different part of the
尽管您可能希望将引用传递给程序的不同部分
program borrowing allows you to access a reference in memory without taking
借用允许您访问内存中的引用而不取得
ownership of it there are a ton of rules to go along with this system that the
它的所有权 这个系统有很多规则
rus borrow checker will validate at compile time these rules keep your code
rus 借用检查器将在编译时验证这些规则可确保您的代码
safe while providing absolute control over performance rust also has a package
安全，同时提供对性能的绝对控制 rust 还有一个
manager called cargo where each individual package is a crate to get
名为 cargo 的包管理器，其中每个单独的包都是一个板条箱，
started install rest then run cargo new from the command line in the main.rs
开始安装 rest 然后从命令行运行 cargo new在 main.rs
file you'll find a main function which is where the program will start
文件中，您会找到一个 main函数，程序将在该函数中开始
executing declare a variable with let followed by its name and type the value
执行声明一个变量，后面跟着 let 根据其名称和类型
can't be changed or reassigned by default so add mutt to make it mutable
，默认情况下无法更改或重新分配值，因此添加 mutt 以使其可变
the name of the variable is the owner a reference to its location in memory can
变量的名称是所有者对其在内存中位置的引用可以
be borrowed by other parts of the program by prefixing it with an
通过添加前缀被程序的其他部分借用 使用
ampersand then use a macro like print line to log the value to the standard
＆符号，然后使用类似打印行的宏将值记录到标准
output rest also comes with a standard library that contains modules to handle
输出 rest 还附带一个标准库，其中包含处理
io the file system concurrency among many other things now compile your code
io 文件系统并发以及许多其他事情的模块 现在使用 rust 编译器将您的代码编译
to an executable with the rust compiler you just built a memory safe executable
为可执行文件您刚刚构建了一个内存安全的可执行文件
that can handle the most performance intensive system requirements this has
，它可以处理性能最密集的系统要求，这
been rust in 100 seconds hit the like button and subscribe if you want to see
已经在 100 秒内生锈，如果您想看更多这样的短视频，请点击“赞”按钮并订阅，如果您想看完整的
more short videos like this and leave a comment if you want to see a full rust
视频，请发表评论 rust
tutorial thanks for watching and i will see you in the next one
教程感谢观看，下一篇再见